<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles of agreement, concluded, made, and agreed on this twenty eight day of May, in the year of our Lord, one thousand six hundred ninety and four, between the royal free burrows, cities, and others of their Majesties antient kingdom of Scotland, who shall be pleased to subscribe, and be concerned in the Scots linen-subscription-book, for the linen-manufacture in that kingdom of the one part; and Nicolas Dupin of the city of London Esquire, in trust for the members and subscribers who shall be hereafter pleased to subscribe, and be concerned in the aforesaid linen-manufacture in England, of the other part.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01440</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3833B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R233252</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52528734</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52528734</idno>
            <idno type="VID">178698</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01440)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 178698)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2766:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles of agreement, concluded, made, and agreed on this twenty eight day of May, in the year of our Lord, one thousand six hundred ninety and four, between the royal free burrows, cities, and others of their Majesties antient kingdom of Scotland, who shall be pleased to subscribe, and be concerned in the Scots linen-subscription-book, for the linen-manufacture in that kingdom of the one part; and Nicolas Dupin of the city of London Esquire, in trust for the members and subscribers who shall be hereafter pleased to subscribe, and be concerned in the aforesaid linen-manufacture in England, of the other part.</title>
                  <author>Dupin, Nicholas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>15, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained, print show-through with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Linen industry --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Linen industry --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:178698:1"/>
            <head>ARTICLES of AGREEMENT,</head>
            <argument>
               <p> Concluded, Made, and Agreed on this Twenty eight Day of <hi>May,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand ſix hundred ninety and four, between the Royal Free Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rows, Cities, and others of Their Majeſties Antient Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> who ſhall be pleaſed to Subſcribe, and be Concerned in the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen-Subſcription-Book, for the Linen-Manufacture in that Kingdom of the one Part; AND <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> Eſquire, in Trust for the Members and Subſcribers who ſhall be hereafter pleaſed to Subſcribe, and be Concerned in the aforeſaid Linen-Manufacture in <hi>England,</hi> of the other Part.</p>
            </argument>
            <p>1. <hi>IMprimis,</hi> That it is Declared and Agreed, that there ſhall be a general Joynt Stock of Thirty Thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling,</hi> to carry on the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen-Manufacture in the aforeſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> and that the ſaid Stock ſhall be divided into ſixty hundred Shares, or Parts, in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form following; That is to ſay, Thirty hundred Shares or Parts, being the one Moyety of the aforeſaid Sixty hundred Shares, ſhall be Subſcribed by the Subſcribers in the aforeſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> who ſhall hereafter Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe for the ſame, at Five Pound <hi>Sterling</hi> for each and every one of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Thirty Hundred Shares.</p>
            <p>2. <hi>Item,</hi> That there ſhall be Thirty hundred Shares, or Parts more to be Subſcribed for in <hi>England,</hi> by the Subſcribers who ſhall Subſcribe for the ſame at five Pound
<hi>Sterling,</hi> as aforeſaid, for each and every one of the aforeſaid Thirty hundred Shares, being the other Moyetie of the aforeſaid Sixty hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:178698:2"/>Shares, which ſaid ſixty hundred Shares, at five Pound <hi>Sterling per</hi> each, and every Share amounts to the ſum of Thirty thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling,</hi> as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, and the ſame to be paid at four ſeveral even and equal Payments, THAT IS TO SAY, The Sum of One Pound five Shillings <hi>Sterling,</hi> being the firſt Payment to be paid to the
<hi>Scots</hi> and <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen-Treaſurers, hereafter to be choſen at the Cities of
<hi>Edinburgh</hi> and <hi>London,</hi> for each Shate they ſhall Subſcribe for, on the firſt Day of <hi>Nevember</hi> next enſuing, the Date of theſe Preſents, or within fourteen Days then next following; and the like Sum of One Pound five Shilling Sterling more, being the ſecond Payment to be paid on the firſt Day of <hi>May</hi> then next following, or within fourteen Days then next after, which will be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand ſix hundred ninety five; and the like Sum of One Pound five Shilling <hi>Sterling</hi> more, being the Third Payment to be paid on the firſt Day of <hi>November</hi> then next following, or within fourteen Days then next after. And laſtly, The like Sum of One Pound five Shillings <hi>Sterling</hi> more, being the fourth and laſt Payment, to be paid on the firſt Day of <hi>May,</hi> then next following, or within fourteen Days then next after, which will be in the Year of our Lord, One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſix hundred ninety ſix.</p>
            <p>3. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Agreed, That in caſe any Subſcribers in the aforeſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> ſhould not pay in, or cauſe to be paid in to the <hi>Scots</hi> Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen Treaſurer, at the City of <hi>Edinburgh</hi> for the time, being the aforeſaid Sum of One Pound five Shillings <hi>Sterling,</hi> being the firſt Payment to be paid on the firſt
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, or within fourteen, Days thence next following, as before limited; That then and in that caſe, ſuch Perſon or Perſons Subſcriptions ſhall be void, to all Intents and Purpoſes, as if he or they had never ſubſcribed; and that then it ſhall and may be lawful to, and for the <hi>Scots</hi> Society and Subſeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, or Major Part of them, at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> to have full Power and Authority, to Nom in at and Appoint a Committee, conſiſting of ſix Perſons at leaſt, who ſhall have full Power to Sell and Transfer into the Transfer-Book, or Books, to be provided for that purpoſe under the Common Seal, or other ways of the ſald <hi>Scots</hi> Society and Subſcribers, as aforeſaid, all, or any of the ſaid Shares when Forefeited, as aforeſaid to ſuch Perſon or Perſons, who ſhall be willing to buy the aforeſaid ſhares ſo Forfeited, as aforeſaid, at the ſame price and rate as they were firſt Subſcribed for. And the ſaid Money for the ſaid Shares to be to the uſe of the Joynt Linen Stock, and that then the ſaid ſhares ſo Transferred, ſhall be good and valid to the New Purchaſer, to all Intents and Purpoſes.</p>
            <p>4. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Agreed, That in caſe any Subſcribers in the aforeſaid Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> ſhould not pay in, or cauſe to be paid in to the
<hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Treaſurer, at the City of <hi>London,</hi> for the time being, the aforeſaid Sum of One Pound five Shillings <hi>Sterling,</hi> being the firſt Payment to be paid on the
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:178698:2"/>ſaid firſt Day of <hi>November</hi> next, or within fourteen Days then next following, as before limited; that then and in ſuch caſe, ſuch Perſon or Perſons Subſcriptions ſhall be void to all Intents and Purpoſes, as if he or they had never Subſcribed; and that then it ſhall and may be alſo lawful to, and for the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Society and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribers, or major part of them, at the ſaid City of <hi>London,</hi> to have full Power and Authority, to Nominat and Appoint a Committee, conſiſting of ſix Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons at leaſt, who ſhall have full Power and Authority to Sell and Transfer into the Transfer Book or Books, provided for that purpoſe, under the Common Seal, or otherways of the ſaid
<hi>Engliſh</hi> Society, or ſubſcribers as aforeſaid, all, or any the ſaid Forefeited ſhares aforeſaid, to ſuch Perſon or Perſons who ſhall be willing to buy the aforeſaid Shares, ſo Forfeited as aforeſaid, at the ſame price and rate as they were firſt Subſcribed for, and the ſaid Money for the ſaid Shares to be to the uſe of the general joynt Linen-Stock; and that then the ſaid Shares ſo Transferred, ſhall be good and valid to the New Purchaſer, to all Intents and Purpoſes.</p>
            <p>5. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That in caſe of failour of payment in of all, eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, or any of the aforeſaid remaining three reſpective Sums of One Pound five Shilling Sterling
<hi>per</hi> Share, in the above Articles meentioned as aforeſaid, to be paid at the ſeveral Days of Payment above limited, according to the true In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent and Meaning thereof, for the ſpace of one Month next after any of the ſaid Days of Payment, on which the ſame ought to be paid, as aforeſaid, that then and in ſuch caſe, every ſuch Perſon or Perſons, making ſuch Deſault, which hinders the Trade, for non-payment, ſhall from time to time, upon every ſuch failure reſpectively Forfeit and pay to the Linen Treaſurer, in any the ſaids King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms, where ſuch Forfeiture for non-payment, ſhall be the Sum of five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings <hi>Sterling per</hi> each Share for the time being in Committee aſſembled, for the uſe and benefit of the general joynt Linen Stock, for each and every ſhare and ſhares that ſhall be ſo unpaid for, and in arrear, until all the Money due for the ſaid Shares, and all the ſaid Penalties, Arrears, and Forfeitures due for the ſame, ſhall be fully ſatisfied, contented and payed, and that the Share and Shares of each and every ſuch Perſon or Perſons making ſuch Default as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall from time to time, and at all times hereafter, be ſubject and lyable to all ſuch payments, penalties and forfeitures, until the full value of the ſaid Shares of ſuch Perſon or Perſons, ſo in arrear be ſpent out and determined, and the ſaid Shares to be ſold and diſpoſed of by the Linen Committee of Trade, hereafter to be choſen, to any Perſon who will give moſt for the ſaids ſhares, to anſwer the aforeſaid Debts.</p>
            <p>6. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, that there ſhall be two Linen Treaſurers cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen, <hi>viz.</hi> One Treaſurer to be choſen at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> by the plurality of Votes of the joynt Proprietars in <hi>Scotland;</hi> And another Treaſurer
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:178698:3"/>to be choſen at the City of <hi>London,</hi> by the plurality of Votes of the joynt Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietars in <hi>England:</hi> Which afoteſaid two Treaſurers ſhall give good and ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient Security in <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>England,</hi> to the liking and Satisfaction of the Major part of all the joynt Proprietars for the time being, and that the ſaid Treaſurer and Treaſurers ſhall be choſen immediatly after, and ſo ſoon as the ſubſcription Book or Books are filled and ſhut up, which will be on or about the firſt day of <hi>November</hi> next enſuing the date of theſe Preſents, or within fourteen days then next after.</p>
            <p>7. <hi>Item,</hi> That the ſaid Linen Treaſurers, ſhall make up their Accompts in both Kingdoms once in every four Months, of what Money they have received. and what Money they have payed out, and what Money they have in their hands, and what Debts are due to the Company, and by whom due, and where the ſaid Mony is lodged; and give an account of the ſame in writting, to the Courts and Committees at <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and in <hi>London,</hi> and ſend a true Coppie of the ſame to each Kingdom: and that the ſaid Treaſurers ſhall not pay any Money out of the Linen joynt Stack they nor either of them ſhall have in their hands without a warrand firſt Signed by five Affiſtants, at leaſt the Governour, Deputy Governour, or Chair-men hereafter to be choſen at the next General Court, to be always one of the five.</p>
            <p>8. <hi>Item,</hi> That there ſhall be two Books for Subſcriptions, and Transſerrs, and whatſoever Orders, Penalties and Laws, ſhall be write and Signed in one Book, ſhall be alſo write and Signed in the other, with the ſeveral Seal or Seals of the Subſcribers in each Kingdom of <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>England;</hi> And that one of the ſaids two Books ſhall be kept by the ſaids <hi>Scots</hi> Society at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> or by ſuch perſons as the Linen Court, or grand Committee, or Major part of them in that City ſhall think fit: ſuch Book keepers giving good Security to the liking and Satisfaction of the ſaid Court, or Grand Committe aforeſaid: And another of the ſaid Books to be kept by a Commitee thereafter mentioned, as the plurality of Votes of the joynt Proprietars in the City of <hi>London</hi> ſhall think fit, he giving ſuch Security to the ſaid <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Committee as aforeſaid: Which ſaid two Subſcription Books ſhall not be removed out of one Kingdom into another, after that theſe Subſcription Books are filled and delivered to each Kingdom, on pain to forfeit the Sum of One Thouſand Pound <hi>Sterling,</hi> to be payed in to the Linen Treaſurers for the time, being by the Linen Members of that Kingdom, who ſhall ſuffer their own Transfert Books to be removed out of one Kingdom into another as aforeſaid: and the ſaid One Thouſand Pound, when Forfeited, to be payed to the Sole uſe and benefite of the general Joynt Linen Stock.</p>
            <p>9. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, that it ſhall and may be lawful, to and for the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Society, to Sell and Transferr their own Shares, or any number of them
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:178698:3"/>they ſhall Subſcribe for in <hi>Edinburgh</hi> in their own Transferr Books; And <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhall and may be alſo lawful, to and for the ſaid <hi>Engliſh</hi> Societie, to Sell and
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ferr their own Shares, or any number of them they have Subſcribed for, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therways in their own Transferr Book at <hi>London.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>10. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, that thereſhall be in the ſaid City of
<hi>Edinburgh,</hi> in the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Company, thirty Affiſtants. and out of the ſaid thirty Affi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants a Governour, Deputy Governour, and Treaſurer ſhall be Elected and choſen, But in caſe there ſhall be no Governour, nor Deputy Governour E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected or choſen as aforeſaid, that then in ſuch caſe, there ſhall be a Chairman choſen in their Rooms; Which aforeſaid thirty Aſſiſtants, Governour, Deputy Governour, Treaſurer or Chairman ſhall be choſen by the pluralitie of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars at <hi>Edinburgh</hi> in
<hi>Scotland,</hi> at the firſt General Court or Grand Meeting, which will be on or about the firſt day of <hi>November</hi> next, or within fourteen days next after.</p>
            <p>11. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, that there ſhall be in the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Company at <hi>London,</hi> thirty Affiſtants, and out of the aforeſaid thirty Affiſtants, a Chair-man ſhall be Elected and choſen, which aforeſaid thirty Affiſtants and Chairman ſhall and may be choſen by the plurality of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars at the ſaid City of <hi>London</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> at the firſt General Court or Grand Meeting there, which will be on or about the aforeſaid firſt day of <hi>November</hi> next, or within fourteen days then next after.</p>
            <p>12. <hi>Item,</hi> That a Committee of Trade conſiſting of ſix Perſons, ſhall always Annually be choſen, nominated and appointed out of the aforeſaid thiry Affi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, for to meet and ſit at the City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> in the ſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> as often as neceſſary occaſion ſhall Require: in manner and Form following. That is to ſay, The Committee and Members at <hi>London,</hi> who ſhall have the Major part, or greateſt numbers of Shares, ſhall and may have full power and liberty to chooſe, nominat and appoint three perſons, whereof their principle Agent for the time being may be always one, to direct, Sir, ſerve and Affiſt in the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Committee of Trade at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh.</hi> AND in like manner, the Governour or Chair-man, and Affiſtants of the
<hi>Scots</hi> Linen Society for the time being; may have liberty to chooſe nominat and appoint three perſons, to ſit with the other aforeſaid three perſons, which together makes up the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid ſix to be a Committee of Trade: to ſit, direct, ſerve and Affiſt in the ſaid
<hi>Scots</hi> Society, and Committee of Trade at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh;</hi> Which ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Committee ſo choſen, ſhall have a Competent allowance out of the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Joynt Stock for their trouble and pains, Reſerving to the plurality of Votes of the Major part of the Joynt Proprietars in both Kingdoms, power to increaſs or leſſen the number of Agents as they ſhall think fit.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:178698:4"/>13. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo agreed, that the Subſcribers ſhall have liberty to transfer <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> own Shares in their own Transfer-books in each Kingdom, at the lawful and uſual days and times; and the ſaid Books not to be ſhut without the Conſent of the Major Part of all the Joynt Proprietars in each Kingdom.</p>
            <p>14. <hi>Item,</hi> It is mutually agreed, that the Committee at <hi>London,</hi> ſhall be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted, &amp; have notice from the Commmittee of Trade &amp; Store-keeper at
<hi>Edin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burgh,</hi> of all the Quantities &amp; ſeveral forts of Linen, the Lengths &amp; Breadths each Piece contains, &amp; to ſend Patrons of each ſort of Cloath they have in the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny-ſtore <hi>Edinburgh</hi> to the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Company at <hi>London,</hi> for them to ſee and try what each ſort of Cloath is beſt &amp; moſt Mercatable, &amp; what each ſort of Cloath will yield and be ſold for <hi>per</hi> Yard, Eln, or whole Piece, and to ſend notice thereof to the Court or Committee of Trade at the City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and the ſaid Committee of Trade to enquire into the ſeveral Prices, of the ſeveral forts of Linen Cloath, and to examine and compare the Prices, that ſuch ſorts of Cloath yield in <hi>Scotland,</hi> and what ſuch ſorts of Cloath yield in <hi>England,</hi> with the Coſts and Charges, by ſending of ſuch Cloath to the Linen Committee at <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforeſaid, and all ſuch ſorts of Cloath that ſhall appear and Prove to yield the moſt Profit in <hi>England,</hi> (the Coaſts and Charges being allowed) all ſuch ſaid Linen Cloath ſhall be ſent to the
<hi>Scots</hi> Linen Committee at <hi>London,</hi> to be diſpoſed of to the beſt Mercat, in ſuch Quantities, and at ſuch proper Seaſons and Times, as ſhall be reaſonably ordered and appointed by the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen Committees of Trade: And if it ſhould happen the ſaid Committee and Court of Affiſtants, ſhould not agree in ſending up the Linen Cloath in ſuch manner as aforeſaid, or that any other great Differences ſhould happen, that then in ſuch Caſe, the aforeſaid Comitte of Trade ſhall acquaint the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour or Chair-man in Court aſſembled for the time being, where ſuch Diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences may be fully heard, debated, and determined. Upon their not agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, the Governour, Deputy-Governour, or Chair-man, ſhall immediatly call a general Court of all the Joynt Proprietars in <hi>Scotland</hi> and
<hi>England,</hi> where all ſuch Differences ſhall be heard, debated, and determined by the Major part of all the Joynt-Proprietars; and in caſe there ſhould be an Equality of Votes, that then in ſuch caſe, the Governour, Deputy-Governour, or Chair-man ſhall have the caſting Vote: But in caſe no general Court ſhould be called as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, that then in ſuch caſe, the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Treaſurer ſhall ſtop payment of any Money to carry on the Trade, until a general Court is called, on pain of Forfeiting his Place, if he does not ſtop payment as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>15. <hi>Item,</hi> That the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Cloath above-mentioned, ſhall be ſent up to
<hi>London</hi> as aforeſaid, with a Letter of Advice to the Treſaurer, or Store<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper belonging to the ſaid Linen Committee at <hi>London</hi> for the time being, with a juſt and true Accompt of what Sorts and Quantities of Linen Cloath, they ſhall from time to time ſend up to <hi>London</hi> as aforeſaid, and the ſame to be
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:178698:4"/>ſold and diſpoſed of to the beſt Mercat, according to ſuch Allotements and Prices as ſhall be made for the Sale thereof by one perſon, to be choſen by the
<hi>Scots</hi> Linen Comittee at <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> together with another perſon to be cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen by the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Committee at <hi>London,</hi> or Major part of them.</p>
            <p>16. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further declared, that the Linen Committee of Trade at
<hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinburgh</hi> ſhall enquire into what ſorts of Cloath are moſt profitable in
<hi>Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> to be ſold to the beſt Mercat there: And all ſuch Cloath as ſhall appear to be more profitable to be ſold in <hi>Scotland,</hi> for the Good and Profit of the gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Joynt Linen Stock, than the ſame can be ſold for in <hi>England,</hi> ſhall be ſold in <hi>Scotland;</hi> and the Money for the ſaid Linen Cloath ſhall be payed into the
<hi>Scots</hi> Linen Treſaurer, for the uſe of the Joynt Linen Stock at the ſame time the Cloath is delivered by the Store-keeper to the Buyers, but in caſethe Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Trade in
<hi>Edinburgh</hi> ſhall know the Buyers to be ſufficient and reſponſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble perſons, and the Buyers to allow a reaſonable Conſideration for the ſpace of three or four Moneths Forbearance of paying the Money, which ſhall be due for the ſaid Cloath they ſhall ſo buy of the ſaid Linen Company, that in ſuch caſes, the Committee of Trade ſhall allow them ſuch time for payment above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, as they the ſaid Committee of Trade ſhall think fit at
<hi>Edinburgh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>17. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo agreed, that the Length Breadth of every whole Piece, or half Piece of Linen Cloath, of all the ſeveral ſorts to be made in the <hi>Scots</hi>-Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen Society, ſhall be ſettled and a Leaden-ſeal to be aff<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>ixt to the end of each Piece, the better to diſtinguiſh the Company Linen Cloath from others.</p>
            <p>18. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo agreed, that there ſhall be likewiſe a Committee of Trade, conſiſting of ſix perſons choſen by the Plurality of Votes of the Joynt Propri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>etars in
<hi>England,</hi> to ſit and do Buſineſs for the Good of the general Linen Joynt Stock in the City of <hi>London;</hi> and that a Chair-man ſhall be choſen, out of the ſix aforeſaid Members to ſit with them, and the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Cloath that ſhall be ſend to
<hi>London</hi> to be ſold, there ſhall be delivered to the Store-keeper, who ſhall give good and ſufficient Security to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Court and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee at <hi>London,</hi> and that it ſhall be in the power of the aforeſaid Linen Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Trade at <hi>London</hi> to truſt any perſon or perſons, who ſhall buy any Quantity of the Companies <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Cloath for the ſpace and time of three or four Moneths, provided they know the Buyers to be ſufficient and reſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſable perſons, and the Buyers to allow a reaſonable Conſideration for the Forebearance of the Money, according as the ſaid Committee ſhall think fit, &amp; the ſaid Money for the ſaid Linen Cloath ſo ſold, ſhall (when due) be payed into the
<hi>London</hi> Linen Treſaurer at <hi>London,</hi> to be by him returned to the <hi>Scots</hi> Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen Treſaurer at the City of <hi>Edinburgh</hi> for the time being, for the uſe of the
<hi>Scots</hi> Linen Joynt Stock within thirty days next after the Receipt of ſuch Parts of Parcels of ſuch Linen Cloath, with a juſt and perfect Accompt of the ſame, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether with th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> benefit of the current Exchange for the time being.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:178698:5"/>19. <hi>Item,</hi> It's further declared, that what Coſts and Charges ſhall be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penced for Fraught Carriages and Storage, or any other Expenſes or Charges relating to the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi>-Companies Linnen-cloath, the ſame ſhall be payed and allowed out of the
<hi>Scots</hi> general Linnen joint-ſtock.</p>
            <p>20. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further declared, that a juſt Dividend of all the Profit, ſhall be made at a juſt and reaſonable convenient time, by the general conſent of the plurality of Votes, of all the joint Proprietars in the aforeſaid two Kingdoms of the <hi>Scots</hi>-Linnen Joint-ſtocks; And, that it ſhall be lawful for any Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribers and Members, to Transfer all, or any of their own Shares, to any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons whom they ſhall think fit, into the Companies Transfer-books at the ſeveral and convenient time or times; but it ſhall not be lawful for any Member to withdraw his or their Stock, nor any part thereof, out of the gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Joint ſtock of the <hi>Scots</hi> Linnen-Company, nor the general Joint-ſtock be diſſolved, but the ſaid Stock ſhall remain, to be imployed to carry on the Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen Manufacture in
<hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>21. <hi>Item,</hi> Whereas there is but thirty hundred Shares to be ſubſcribed for in the Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> It is hereby declared, that the thirty hundred ſharer ſhall be divided and ſubſcribed in manner following, That is to ſay, Twelve hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred ſhares to be ſubſcribed in the City of <hi>Edinburgh;</hi> To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Perth,</hi> ſixty five ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Dundee,</hi> eighty five ſhares. To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Aberdeen,</hi> one hundred and twenty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Stirling,</hi> forty five ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lithgow,</hi> fourty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of St. <hi>Andrews,</hi> twenty ſhares, To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Glaſgow,</hi> three hundred and thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Air,</hi> fourty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Haddingtoun</hi> fifty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Dyſert,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Roys Burrow of <hi>Kirkaldy,</hi> ſixty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Montroſs,</hi> fifty-five ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Couper,</hi> twenty five ſhares; To the Roys Burrow of <hi>Anſtruther</hi> Eaſter, ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Drumfreis</hi> fifty five ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Inverneſs,</hi> fifty ſhares; To the Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Burrow of <hi>Burnt-Iſland,</hi> twenty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Innerkeith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Kinghorn,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Breichen,</hi> fitteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Irving</hi> twenty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Jedburgh,</hi> fourty ſhares; To the Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Burrow of <hi>Kirkubright,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Wigton</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Pittenweem,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Dumfermling,</hi> twenty eighth ſhares; To the Royal Burrow <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <hi>Anſtruther</hi> Weſter, five ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Selkirk,</hi> twenty three ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Dumbarton,</hi> twelve ſhares; To the Royal Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row of
<hi>Renfrew,</hi> fitteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Dumbar,</hi> twenty ſhare
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:178698:5"/>To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Lanerk,</hi> twenty ſhares; To the Royal
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Aberbrothick,</hi> eighteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Elgine,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Peebles,</hi> twenty ſhares; To the Royal
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Craill,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Tayn,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Culroſs,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Bainff,</hi> ſix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Whithorn,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Forfar,</hi> twelve ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Rothſay,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Nairn,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Cullen,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Lauder,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Forres,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Rutherglen,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>North-berwick,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Rurrow of <hi>Kilreny,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Annan,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Senquhar,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Galloway,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Dingwal,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row of <hi>Dornoch,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Queens-ferry,</hi> twenty ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Fortroſs,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Kintore,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of
<hi>Innerara,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Inverurie,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Wcik,</hi> fifteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Kirkwal,</hi> thirty five ſhares; To the Royal Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row of <hi>Innerbervie,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Strathnaver,</hi> ten ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Lochmaben,</hi> thirteen ſhares; To the Royal Burrow of <hi>Cromartie,</hi> ſeventeen ſhares.</p>
            <p>22. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further declared, that in caſe at any time hereafter, there ſhall be neceſſary occaſion for to encreaſe the aforeſaid general Joynt Linen-ſtock of thirty thouſand pound <hi>Sterling,</hi> for the better carrying on of the ſaid Linen-Trade in the ſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> that no Sum or Sums of money, ſhall be raiſed or borrowed for the time being, unleſs the ſame be upon a juſt and reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Occaſion, and as the ſaid Linen-Trade ſhall require the ſame. And in caſe any Sum or Sums of money ſhal be hereafter raiſed, to carry on the ſaid Trade as aforeſaid, That then the ſame ſhall be laid out, and imployed to the ſole and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per uſe of the ſaid Linen-Trade, and all things relating thereto, and not other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways; and that the ſaid Money ſo to be raiſed, ſhall not at any one time ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the Sum of one pound <hi>Sterling per</hi> each of the aforeſaid ſixty hundred ſhares, in one Year at moſt; which ſaid one pound <hi>Sterling per</hi> each ſhare, will amount unto the Sum of ſix thouſand pound <hi>Sterling;</hi> provided always, that the Members of the Linen-Company, have lawful and due notice ſent to them two Months before ſuch payment, that they may have due time to provide the ſame. But in caſe any of the ſaid Members ſhould not pay in, or cauſe to be payed in, the aforeſaid Sum of one pound <hi>Sterling per</hi> ſhare, they have in the Joynt ſtock, according to the time limited to the Linen-Treaſurer, or Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurers,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:178698:6"/>for the uſe aforeſaid, that then, and in ſuch Caſe, it ſhall be lawful for the Committee of Trade; to Sell and diſpoſe, of one or more of the ſaid, Perſons Shares, ſo in Arrear to any Perſon or Perſons, who ſhall give moſt for the ſaid Shares, for to Pay and anſwer the Arrears and Debts, ſuch ſaid Members owes to the Company: But no more Share of ſuch Members, ſo in Arreats, ſhall be ſold, then what ſhall prove ſufficient to anſwer the Debt, due by him to the Company; And in Caſe there ſhould be any over plus of Money left, after the ſaid Shares are Sold, and ſuch Perſons Debt ſatisfied and Payed, that then ſuch overplus ſhall be juſtly returned, and payed unto the aforeſaid Member. And it is alſo Declared, that no Member ſhall be lyable to be ſued by Law, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in perſon or Eſtate, by reaſon of any Debt he owes to the Company, relating to his Shares, he has in the Joynt Stock, but the Shares of ſuch perſon of perſons, to be only anſwerable for his, or their Debts, he owes to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies Joynt Linen Stock.</p>
            <p>23. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, and thought Reaſonable and neceſſary, that the Joynt Proprietars-ſhall be Informed once in every three Months of all Proceedings, that they may give their beſt Advice and Aſſiſtance, for the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying on of the ſaid Trade.</p>
            <p>24. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Agreed, that a General Court ſhall be called, and fit four times every Year at the leaſt, at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and that due notice thereof ſhall be given to all the Proprietars in both Kingdoms, or their Agents: Who ſhall give the Proprietars due notice of the ſame, by Affixing an Advertiſement in writing, upon the Mercat-Croſs of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and at the Royal Exchange in the City of <hi>London;</hi> Twenty days before any ſuch of the aforeſaid General Court ſhall fit. That is to ſay, the firſt General Court to be held on or about the firſt day of <hi>November</hi> next, enſuing the date of theſe preſent or within fourteen days then next after, the ſecond General Court to be held on the firſt day of <hi>February</hi> then next after, or within fourteen days then next after, the third General Court to be held on the firſt day of <hi>May,</hi> then next en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing, or within fourteen days then next after: The fourth General Court to be held, on the firſt day of <hi>August</hi> then next enſuing, or within fourteen days then next after, which will be in the Year of our LORD, One Thouſand <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Hundred Ninety-Five.</p>
            <p>25. <hi>Item.</hi> It is alſo Declared, that it ſhall, and may be lawful to, and
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the chiefeſt Agents of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Subſcribers, or Major part of them, to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> choſen off, and added to the Grand Committee, of the ſaid <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Society at
<hi>Edinburgh:</hi> They the ſaids Agents, having lawful notice from time to time given them of ſuch Committee for them, to be there when they pleaſe, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:178698:6"/>ſhall, and may be alſo always of the Linen Courts and Committees of Accompts and all others now and hereafter to be ſettled Linen Committees, or Managing the ſaid Trade. And may have free liberty at all times hereafter, to Overſee, and Inſpect the Treaſurers Accompts, and all other Accompts relating to the ſaid Linen Manufactory, and to Coppy out the ſame, and to ſend true Coppies thereof, to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Commitee at
<hi>London,</hi> if they think fit, the ſaid <hi>Engliſh</hi> Agents to be Payed by the
<hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Committee.</p>
            <p>26. <hi>Item,</hi> For all other matters, or things not herein or hereby Expreſt, contained or provided for, that if any difference ſhall hereafter ariſe, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning theſe preſent Articles, and Linen, or any differences concerning the ordering or Managing the ſaid Linen Trade: That then, ſuch differences ſhall be ſettled, Agreed, and compoſed by the plurality of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars of both Kingdoms, at the next General Court, next following, at the aforeſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>27. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, and Agreed, that there ſhall be ſix Truſtees nominated and appointed, to whom the General Joynt Linen Stock ſhall be Aſſigned, and made over in Truſt, for the whole Linen Company in both Kingdoms; Which ſaid ſix Truſtees, ſhall give good and ſufficient Security, to the liking and Satisfaction of the Major part of all the Joynt Proprietars, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned in the General Joynt Linen Stock: Three of which ſaid ſix Truſtees ſhall and may be choſen at the ſaid City of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> by the plurality of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars in <hi>Scotland:</hi> And the other three Truſtees, which makes up the aforeſaid ſix Truſtees, ſhall, and may be choſen in the City of
<hi>London,</hi> by the plurality of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars in <hi>England;</hi> Provided always, the aforeſaid ſix Truſtees ſhall be obliged to re-deliver up the aforeſaid Truſt to the Linen Company, at any time, when by the plurality of Votes, of all the Joynt Proprietars in both Kingdoms, of the General Joynt Linen Stock, ſhall be thereunto required, as Free from Encumbrances, as they had the ſame.</p>
            <p>28. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, that the Subſcribers ſhall have a Certificat under the Common Seal, or otherways, of the ſaid Linnen Company, for each one Share they ſhall ſubſcribe for in the Linen Subſcription Books, wherein ſhall be mentioned the ſeveral Days, and Quarterly Times of Payments, as in the Articles limited: and when ſoever the Subſcribers minds to diſpoſe and Transfer in the Companys Transfer-Books, any of his Shares, to any perſon or perſons whatſomever, ſuch Members ſhall at the ſame time of the Transfer, deliver to the Purchafer, or otherways his Certificat relating to the ſame, for each and every Share he ſhall ſo diſpoſe of, to the perſon to whom he Transfers the ſaid Shares.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:178698:7"/>29. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, and Agreed by all and every the Subſcribers, now and hereafter, to be concerned in the Scots Linen Subſcription Book, and Joynt Stock that <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> Eſquire or his order ſhall have, and receive from each, and every Subſcriber, the Sum of Eight Shilling <hi>Sterling,</hi> for each and every ones Share, they and every one of them ſhall Subſcribe for, to be Payed to him, the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> or his order as aforeſaid, upon Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription, he or his order giving a receipt under the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> his hand, ſigned for the ſame, which aforeſaid Eight Shilling <hi>Sterling,</hi> being in conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin,</hi> his great coſts and charges, pains and Induſtry, in promoting and helping to Procure Subſcriptions, for the raiſing a General Joynt Stock, and his Traveling in charges from one Kingdom into another, to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote and encourage the Linen Manufactory, in the ſaid Kingdom of
<hi>Scotland;</hi> and for his ſeveral other Charges, and Expences he has, and muſt of neoſſity be at, in promoting and encouraging the ſaid Linen Manufactory, in the ſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>30. <hi>Item.</hi> It is hereby alſo Declared, That whereas ſeveral perſons who have ſubſcribed Twelve hundred ſhares in the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Subſcription Books at
<hi>London</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> and in purſuance of certain Articles in the ſaid Subſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Book, bearing date on, or about the thirteenth Day of <hi>November,</hi> One Thouſand-ſix hundred ninety three, Did pay to <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> Eſquire, the ſum of nineteen ſhillings <hi>ſterling per</hi> each ſhare at ſubſcription: It is hereby Declared and Agreed, That all the aforeſaid Subſcribers who have not ſold, or otherways Diſpoſed of their ſaid Twelve hundred ſhares aforeſaid, or any number of them to other perſons, ſhall have free liberty to come in and ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe in the Subſcription Book, belonging to theſe preſent Articles, for ſo many ſhares as they now have, and have not ſold and diſpoſed of as aforeſaid, in certain Articles, bearing date on or about the ſeventh Day of <hi>February,</hi> One Thouſand ſix hundred ninety three; and the aforeſaid Perſons to be freed from paying the ſum of eight Shillings <hi>ſterling</hi> for each ſhare, which is to be paid to the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> upon ſubſcription, by theſe preſent Articles, and the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> to give the ſaids ſubſcribers aforeſaid his receipt for the eight ſhillings <hi>per</hi> each ſhare aforeſaid, for ſuch number of ſhares they ſhall ſubſcribe for, as if ſuch ſubſcribers had paid down the ſame in <hi>ſpecie;</hi> provided alwayes the ſaids Subſcribers come in, and Subſcribe in the Subſcription Book relating to theſe preſent Articles at <hi>London,</hi> at any time before, Twenty hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of the ſaid thirty hundred Shares in theſe preſent Articles mentioned, ſhall be ſubſcribed for at <hi>London.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:178698:7"/>31. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That whereas by certain Articles, bearing date on or about the ſeventh Day of <hi>February,</hi> One Thouſand ſix hundred ninety three, ſeveral perſons at <hi>Edinburgh</hi> in the Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> have ſubſcribed the number of ſix hundred Shares in the Linen Subſcription Books relating to the aforeſaid Articles, the ſame being part of eighteen hundred shares ſubſcribed in the whole. It is hereby Declared, That all the aforeſaid Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribers, who have not ſold, or otherways diſpoſed of their ſaid Shares, or any number of them, to other perſons, shall have free liberty to come in and ſubſcribe in the ſubſcription Book, belonging to theſe Articles at
<hi>Edinburgh,</hi> for ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Shares as they now have in the aforeſaid Articles, and the aforeſaid perſons to be freed and excepted from paying the ſum of eight Shillings
<hi>Sterling per</hi> each Share, which is to be paid unto the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> upon Subſcription by theſe preſent Articles, and the ſaid <hi>Nicolas Dupin</hi> to give the ſaid Subſcribers his Receipt for the eight Shillings <hi>per</hi> share aforeſaid, for ſuch number of Shares as they shall ſubſcribe for, as if ſuch Subſcribers had paid to him the ſame in <hi>ſpecie;</hi> Provided always the aforeſaid Subſcribers come in and ſubſcribe in the ſubſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion Books, relating to theſe preſent Articles at
<hi>Edinburgh,</hi> at any time before twenty four hundred of the ſaid thirty hundred Shares in theſe preſent Articles mentioned, shall be ſubſcribed at <hi>Edinburgh</hi> in
<hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>32. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That every perſon or perſons ſhall have one Vote for each and every five Shares as he has in the general joynt Stock to Vote for, and if he has to the number of twenty Shares, that then he ſhall have four Votes to vote for at every general Court, but no more.</p>
            <p>33. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, That when ever any of the Courts of aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, or any Committee relating to the Linen, ſhall at any time ſit to do buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, each Member ſhal in that Court and Committee have but one Vote to vote for, and no more.</p>
            <p>34. <hi>Item,</hi> It is further Declared, That no Subſcriber in <hi>Scotland</hi> ſhall have liberty to Subſcribe above Twenty Shares at moſt, at his or their Subſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on (the Chief Royal Burrows aforeſaid only excepted) ſo that they come in before the Books be filled, whilſt there is room to ſubſcribe.</p>
            <p>35. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo further Declared, That the majority of Votes of all the joynt Proprietars of both Kingdoms at a general Court aſſembled, ſhall and may have liberty to make By-Laws, for the better Government of this Linen Manufactory, Provided that ſuch By-Laws ſhall not be contray or repugnant to the Laws of this Kingdom, and ſuch By-Laws ſhall be approved of by ſome of the chiefeſt Judges of the ſaid Kingdom of <hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>36. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That there ſhall be no benefit or advantage ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:178698:8"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, but that each and every perſons intereſt ſhall devolve and come to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Adminiſtrators or Aſſigneys.</p>
            <p>37. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That every perſon who purchaſeth any Shares from the firſt Subſcribers, ſhall accept of the ſaid Shares by Transfer in the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies Books, and ſuch New Purchaſers ſhall be bound and obliged by all and ſingular the Articles above-mentioned, and written as if they were Parties there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to by Name ſubſcribing.</p>
            <p>38. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That no Subſcriber in <hi>London</hi> ſhall be admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to ſubſcribe above twenty Shares, the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Corporation only ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted.</p>
            <p>39. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That if the Linen Treaſurer to be choſen at
<hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinburgh</hi> by the plurality, of Votes, of all the joynt Proprietars in <hi>Scotland,</hi> ſhould at only time hereafter during his Treaſurerſhip, fail, break, or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ways miſcarry with the Companies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, or any ſhare thereof, that then in ſuch caſe the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Company ſhall be reſponſable for the Loſs and Dam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage thereof, to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Company.</p>
            <p>40. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That if the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Treaſurer to be cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen at <hi>London</hi> by the plurality of Votes, of all the joynt Proprietars in
<hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> ſhould at any time hereafter during his Treaſurerſhip, fail, break, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ways miſcarry with the Companies Stock, or any part thereof, that then in ſuch caſe the
<hi>Engliſh</hi> Linen Company ſhall be reſponſable for the Loſs and Dam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage thereby to the <hi>Scots</hi> Linen Company.</p>
            <p>41. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That if the full number of Shares allowed to the Royal Burrows, and Cities in the Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> ſhould not by them be ſubſcribed for by the time hereafter limited next enſuing, that then and in ſuch caſe it ſhall and may be lawful to, and for any other perſon or perſons in <hi>Scotland</hi> to come in and ſubſcribe the remaining part of ſuch Shares as ſhall be left by them unſubſcribed for, as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>42. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That it
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the full number of thirty hundred Shares above-mentioned, to be ſubſcribed for in <hi>Scotland,</hi> ſhould not be full-ſubſcribed for i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that Kingdom by the ſaid fourteenth Day of <hi>October</hi> next enſuing as aforeſaid, that then and in ſuch caſe it shall and may be lawful to and for the Engliſh Nation to ſubſcribe the remaining part of ſuch Shares as shall be left unſubſcribed for in Scotland as aforeſaid, over and above the thirty hundred Shares, allowed to the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>43. <hi>Item,</hi> It is alſo Declared, That in eaſe the thirty hundred Shares above mentioned, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> in <hi>England,</hi> should not be fully ſubſcribed for in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Kingdom by the fourteenth Day of <hi>October</hi> next <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſuing, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:178698:8"/>that then and in ſuch caſe, it shall and may be lawful to, and for
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> perſon or perſons in <hi>Scotland</hi> to come in and ſubſcribe the remaining <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Shares as shall be left ſo unſubſcribed for in <hi>England</hi> as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>44. <hi>Item,</hi> It is Declared, That if any of the Subſcribers shall at any time hereafter be willing to ſell and transfer any of his own Shares to any perſon or perſons, that then in ſuch caſe it shall be lawful for any member of the Linen Company to purchaſe the aforeſaid Shares, it being more reaſonable that any Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the Company should have and buy the ſaid shares than any ſtranger, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding any thing in the Articles before-mentioned to the contrait.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
